TV를 볼 때에는 밝은 방에서 적당히 떨어져서 보도록 해!
While you're watching the television...
Selama menonton acara ini
...be sure to keep your distance and watch in a well-lit room!
pastikan berada di jarak yang cukup dan di ruangan yang terang!
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Dennou Boukenki
Series Composition
Chief Director
Sekijima Mayori
Okajima Kunitoshi
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Oikawa Neko
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
악의 프로그램 데리트로스의 손에서 매지컬 게이트를 되찾기 위해 유우키 켄토는 글라디온과 함께 일어섰다.
To take Magical Gate back from the evil program Deletloss, Yuuki Kento stood up with Gladion.
Yuuki Kento bangkit bersama Gladion untuk merebut kembali Magical Gate dari cengkraman program jahat Deletloss.
매지컬 게이트의 마지막 에이리어, 타임 에이리어에서 다이탈리온과의 전투에 도전한 켄토와 글라디온.
Kento and Gladion engaged in the battle against Ditalion at Time Area, Magical Gate's last area.
Di area terakhir Magical Gate, Time Area, Kento dan Gladion bertarung melawan Ditalion.
그러나 다이탈리온의 안에는 아우 카이토와 아버지 타케토가 갇혀 있었다.
But his brother, Kaito, and his father, Taketo, was trapped inside Ditalion.
Tetapi di dalam tubuh Ditalion, terperangkap adiknya, Kaito, dan ayahnya, Taketo.
가륜과 드라그온의 도움을 받아 둘 다 구한 켄토는 빅토리 글라디온과 함께 다이탈리온을 쓰러뜨렸다.
After saving them with the help of Garyun and Dragwon,
Setelah berhasil menyelamatkan mereka berdua dengan bantuan Garyun dan Dragwon,
Kento took Ditalion down with Victory Gladion.
Kento lalu mengalahkan Ditalion dengan Victory Gladion.
전세계에 평화가 찾아온 것 같아 보였다.
It seemed that peace was all over the world.
Seluruh dunia tampaknya kembali diliputi kedamaian.
그러나 다시 사악한 기운의 폭탄이 다이버랜드를 뒤덮은 것이, 다이탈리온이 아직 살아 있는 것이었다.
But the evil aura bomb threatened Diverland once more; Ditalion was still alive.
Tapi bom energi jahat kembali mengancam Diverland. Ternyata Ditalion masih hidup.
글라디온은 직접 희생해 다이탈리온과 사악한 기운의 폭탄을 막는다.
To stop Ditalion and Evil Aura Bomb, Gladion sacrificed himself.
Gladion mengorbankan dirinya sendiri untuk menghentikan Ditalion dan bom energi jahat.
급히 달려온 켄토가 보는 앞에서 글라디온은 다이탈리온과 함께 소멸하고 만다.
He disappears with Ditalion right in front of Kento's eyes.
Di depan mata Kento, Gladion musnah bersama dengan Ditalion.
글라디온.
Gladion.
글라디온. 안 돼!
Gladion. No!
Gladion. Gawat!
내 시간의 힘이여, 글라디온의 시간을 멈추거라!
I shall stop his time with my power!
Aku akan menghentikan waktunya dengan kekuatanku!
죽게 내버려두지 않는다. 이렇게 생명을 잃을쏘냐, 글라디온!
I will not let you die. I shall not let you die, Gladion!
Tidak akan kubiarkan kau mati. Aku tidak akan membiarkanmu mati, Gladion!
내 생명을 대가로 치루는 한이 있더라도!
Even if it costs my own soul!
Biar harus ditukar dengan jiwaku sekalipun!
마음을 하나로!
Let Hearts Become One!
Satukan Perasaan Kita!
-글라디온을?
-빨리 내가 있는 곳에 오거라, 유우키 켄토.
-Save Gladion?
-Come to my place quickly, Yuuki Kento.
-Untuk menyelamatkan Gladion?
-Segeralah datang ke tempatku, Yuuki Kento.
-어디에, 어디 있어?
-나는 카론 안에 있다.
-Where? Where are you?
-I am inside Karon.
-Dimana? Dimana kau berada?
-Aku ada di dalam Karon.
-서둘러라. 데리트로스가 글라디온을 노리고 있다!
-야, 카론! 야!
-Be quick. Deletloss is targeting on Gladion!
-Hey, Karon! Hey!
-Bergegaslah. Deletloss sedang mengincar Gladion!
-Hei, Karon! Hei!
데리트로스가 글라디온을.
Deletloss wants Gladion.
Deletloss sedang mengincar Gladion.
설마? 켄토에게 뭔 일이?
Don't tell me something happened to Kento?
Jangan-jangan, terjadi sesuatu pada Kento?
아직 전혀...
I still didn't get it.
Lagi-lagi gagal.
모르겠어. 하나도 모르겠어.
I don't understand. I'm really confused.
Aku tidak mengerti. Aku benar-benar bingung.
대체 데리트로스가 뭔지.
Just what in the hell is Deletloss?
Apa, ya, sebenarnya Deletloss itu?
그러니까 그걸 조사하고 있는 것 아니겠니?
And that's exactly why we're trying to find that out.
Justru itu kita mencari tahu.
데리트로스. 그 목적, 근원지 하나 모른다.
Deletloss. None of its objective nor origin is known.
Deletloss. Apa tujuannya? Dimana dia berada? Semuanya masih merupakan misteri.
한시라도 빨리 정체를 밝히지 않으면 매지컬 게이트에서 비극이 다시 일어날 지도 모른다.
If we don't expose him as soon as possible, Magical Gate's tragedy can occur again.
Kalau kita tidak bisa mengetahui dimana keberadaannya, tragedi Magical Gate bisa terulang kembali.
응. 그런 일은 다시는 일어나면 안 돼.
Yeah. I don't want such thing to happen the second time.
Iya. Aku tidak ingin kejadian seperti itu terjadi kedua kalinya.
켄토하고 글라디온은 매지컬 게이트와 다이버랜드를 구해 줬다.
Kento and Gladion have saved Magical Gate and Diverland.
Kento dan Gladion telah menyelamatkan Diverland dan Magical Gate.
이번에는 우리가 데리트로스의 정체를 밝혀 쓰러뜨릴 차례이다.
Now it's our turn to uncover Deletloss' identity and take it down.
Dan kali ini adalah giliran kita untuk mengungkap sosok Deletloss dan sekaligus mengalahkannya.
응. 할아버지, 나도 힘낼게!
That's right! Grandpa, I'll do my best!
Ya! Kakek, aku akan berjuang!
다이탈리온이 카론 안에?
Ditalion is inside Karon?
Ditalion ada di dalam Karon?
-자, 봐봐, 쇼우.
-데리트로스의 반응까지. 그럼,
-Look at this, Shou.
-Reaction of Deletloss is there... That means...
-Coba kau lihat ini, Shou,
-Bahkan ada tanda-tanda Deletloss. Berarti...
쇼우. 설마,
Shou, would it be...
Shou, jangan-jangan...
틀림없어. 다이탈리온은 글라디온을 지키기 위해 싸우고 있는 거야. 데리트로스하고.
There's no mistake.. Ditalion is fighting to protect Gladion from Deletloss.
Tidak salah lagi. Ditalion sedang bertarung melawan Deletloss demi melindungi Gladion.
그럼, 이 작은 반응은 글라디온이네.
So, this small reaction is from Gladion?
Jadi, tanda keberadaan yang kecil ini adalah Gladion, ya?
이렇게 두고 볼 수는 없어. 구하러 가야만 해.
I can't just stand watching that. I must go and save him.
Aku tidak boleh diam saja. Aku harus segera pergi menolongnya.
다이탈리온이 말했어. 글라디온을 구하기 위해서는 내 힘이 필요하다고.
After all, Ditalion did say that he needs my help to save Gladion.
Lagipula, tadi Ditalion juga bilang, untuk menyelamatkan Gladion, dibutuhkan bantuanku.
근데 어떻게 구하러 가게?
But how will you do that?
Tapi bagaimana cara kau menolongnya?
글라디온이 있는 곳은 매지컬 게이트가 아닌 카론 안이잖아.
Gladion is not in Magical Gate. He's inside Karon.
Gladion tidak berada di Magical Gate, melainkan di dalam Karon.
-아, 그렇구나.
-잠깐만.
-Oh, right.
-Wait a second.
-Oh, iya.
-Tunggu sebentar.
왜, 쇼우?
Why, Shou?
Kenapa, Shou?
카론에게도 매지컬 게이트 관리 프로그램이 일부 있다고 했지.
Karon is a part of Magical Gate's administration program, yes?
Karon adalah salah satu bagian dari program pengendali Magical Gate, kan?
응, 직접 그렇게 말했어.
Yeah, he himself told so.
Iya, dia sendiri yang bilang begitu.
그렇다면 매지컬 게이트에 들어갈 때처럼 카론 안에 다이브하면 될지도 몰라.
If that's the case, you might be able to dive inside Karon just like you usually do into Magical Gate.
Mungkin kau bisa melakukan dive ke dalam Karon, seperti halnya ke dalam Magical Gate.
-됐어. 이제 카론 안에 들어가면 돼.
-좋아. 기다려, 글라디온.
-Done. Now you can go into Karon.
-Great! Wait for me, Gladion.
-Berhasil. Dengan begini, kau bisa masuk ke dalam Karon.
-Bagus! Sekarang, tunggu aku, Gladion.
-켄토, 나도 같이 갈게.
-응?
-Kento, I'll go along with you.
-Eh?
-Kento, aku juga ikut denganmu, ya?
글라디온이 모두를 구해 줬잖아. 이번엔 우리가 구할 차례야.
Gladion has saved all of us. Now it's our turn to save him.
Gladion telah menyelamatkan kami semua. Sekarang giliran kita untuk membantunya.
쇼우.
Shou.
응, 가자.
Let's do it!
Ayo!
카론에 플러그 잇!
To Karon, Plug It!
Menuju Karon, Plug It!
-여기가 카론 안이구나...
-가자. 다이탈리온을 찾자.
-So this is how Karon's inside look like.
-Let's go find Ditalion.
-Jadi, ini di dalam Karon, ya?
-Ayo. Kita cari Ditalion.
기능을 완전히 회복했다면 웹몬스터 따위는!
If only my functions had been completely recovered, these Webmonsters would've been nothing!
Seandainya saja seluruh fungsiku sudah pulih kembali, Webmonster seperti ini pasti bisa kumusnahkan!
그래, 데리트로스가 노리는 건 글라디온인가. 두고 보지 않겠다!
Now I see. Deletloss is targeting Gladion. I won't let that happen!
Begitu rupanya. Yang diincar oleh Deletloss adalah Gladion. Ini tidak akan kubiarkan!
다이타 스매시!
Dita Smash!
데리트로스. 네놈에게는 절대 글라디온을 넘겨주지 않겠다!
Deletloss! I won't hand over Gladion to you!
Deletloss! Gladion tidak akan kuserahkan padamu!
-다이탈리온!
-와 주었군, 유우키 켄토!
-Ditalion!
-You're finally here, Yuuki Kento!
-Kau sudah datang, Yuuki Kento!
-너는 쇼우.
-다이탈리온, 글라디온은 어디 있어?
-And you're Kurachi Shou!
-Ditalion, where's Gladion?
-Bukankah kau Kurachi Shou?
-Ditalion, dimana Gladion?
여기다.
Right here.
Di sini.
이건...
This is...
Ini...
-글라디온이다.
-글라디온? 이게?
-Gladion.
-Gladion? This thing is?
-Itu Gladion.
-Gladion? Sekecil ini?
정확히는 글라디온의 코어 프로그램. 웹나이트의 생명이라 부를 수 있는 것이다.
To be exact, that is Gladion's core program. You might call it as Webknight's life.
Lebih tepatnya lagi, itu adalah program inti Gladion. Bisa dibilang, itu adalah jiwa Webknight.
미안하다, 유우키 켄토. 글라디온을 이런 꼴으로.
I am deeply sorry, Yuuki Kento, for making Gladion into such state.
Maaf, Yuuki Kento. Gladion telah jadi seperti itu.
저런! 글라디온, 정신 차려! 글라디온! 글라디온!
That can't be! Pull yourself together, Gladion! Gladion!
Kenapa begini?! Gladion, bertahanlah! Gladion!
뭐, 뭐야.
What was that?
A-Apa ini?
반응하고 있어. 웹다이버의 목소리에 반응하나 봐.
He's reacting. He's reacting to his Webdiver's voice.
Dia bereaksi. Dia bereaksi terhadap suara Webdivernya.
살아 있는 거야, 켄토. 글라디온은 아직 살아있어.
He's alive, Kento. Gladion is still alive.
Dia hidup, Kento. Ternyata Gladion masih hidup.
글라디온.
Gladion.
코어 프로그램이 있다면 글라디온을 부활시킬 수 있다.
As long as we have his core program, Gladion can be revived.
Asalkan program intinya masih ada, Gladion bisa dibangkitkan kembali.
만약 파괴된다면, 그는 다시는...
But if it's destroyed, he will never...
Tapi kalau itu dihancurkan, dia tidak akan pernah bangkit lagi.
그런 일은 없을 거야!
I won't let such thing happen!
Itu tidak akan kubiarkan!
잘 말했다. 글라디온은 목숨을 걸고 날 구해 주었다. 이젠 내 목숨을 걸고 글라디온을 지키겠다.
Exactly. Gladion has saved me by risking his own life. I will protect him no matter what it takes.
Benar katamu. Gladion telah mempertaruhkan nyawa untuk menyelamatkanku.
Aku akan melindunginya, biar harus kutukar nyawaku sekalipun.
다이탈리온. 나도 돕고 싶어. 날... 날 네 웹다이버로 받아 주지 않겠어?
Ditalion, let me help you as well. Would you... would you accept me as your Webdiver?
Ditalion, izinkan aku membantumu. Maukah... maukah kau menjadikanku sebagai Webdivermu?
-쇼우.
-다이탈리온뿐만이 아니야.
-Shou.
-It's not only you, Ditalion.
-Bukan hanya Ditalion saja.
글라디온은 우리를, 매지컬 게이트를 구해 줬어.
Gladion has saved us and Magical Gate, too.
Gladion juga telah menyelamatkan kami, dan juga Magical Gate.
뭔 일을 겪더라도, 쓰러져도, 우리를 구해주기 위해 싸워 줬어.
No matter how many times he fell and got woulded, he kept fighting to save us.
Dia berulang kali terluka, dan jatuhpun, dia tetap berjuang demi menyelamatkan kami.
이번엔 우리가 글라디온을 구할 차례야.
This time, it's our turn to save Gladion.
Kali ini, giliran kita untuk menyelamatkan Gladion.
그러나 나는 네 힘을 악용했다. 그 뿐인가. 네 친구 유우키 켄토와도 싸우게 했지.
But I've abused your power. And that's not all; I even made you fighting against your friend, Yuuki Kento.
Tapi aku telah memperalat kekuatanmu. Bukan hanya itu juga.
Aku bahkan telah membuatmu bertarung melawan sahabatmu, Yuuki Kento.
네 잘못이 아니야. 데리트로스 탓이지. 함께 싸우자.
It's not your fault. It's Deletloss'. Let's fight together.
Itu bukan kesalahanmu. Yang bersalah adalah Deletloss. Mari bertarung bersama.
글라디온을 지키기 위해. 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨리기 위해. 다시는 그 비극이 일어나지 않게 하기 위해!
To protect Gladion. To take down Deletloss. So that the same tragedy won't ever happen again!
Demi melindungi Gladion. Demi mengalahkan Deletloss.
Agar tragedi itu tidak terulang lagi untuk kedua kalinya!
-쇼우.
-알겠다. 너야말로 내 웹다이버다.
-Shou.
-Alright then. You are my Webdiver from now on.
-Baiklah, aku jadikan kau sebagai Webdiverku.
또 온다!
They're approaching again!
Mereka datang lagi!
녀석들은 우리가 맡겠다. 켄토는 그 동안 글라디온을 재생시켜라!
We'll take care of those. Meanwhile, you have to revive Gladion!
Biar kami yang menangani mereka. Sementara itu, kau harus membangkitkan kembali Gladion!
근데 어떻게?
But how?
Tapi, bagaimana caranya?
웹나이트는 웹다이버의 마음과 동기화하면 무한의 힘을 발휘해.
A Webknight can demonstrate an unlimited power when he synchronizes his heart with his Webdiver's.
Bila menyatukan hatinya dengan Webdiver, Webknight bisa mengeluarkan kekuatan yang tidak terbatas.
그러니까 부활하는 것도...
So, reviving him should be possible.
Jadi, bangkit kembalipun bisa dilakukan.
알겠어, 쇼우.
I got it, Shou.
Aku mengerti, Shou.
걱정 마, 글라디온. 반드시 내가 지켜 보일게. 부활시켜 줄게!
Do not worry, Gladion. I'll definitely protect you. I'll revive you!
Jangan khawatir, Gladion. Aku pasti akan melindungimu. Aku akan membangkitkanmu kembali!
자, 켄토. 빨리 가.
Now, Kento, hurry up and go.
Nah, Kento, cepat pergi.
가자! 쇼우!
Let us begin, Shou!
Ayo kita mulai, Shou!
웹다이브! 다이탈리온!
Webdive! Ditalion!
Brought to you by Subdiver
-가자, 다이탈리온!
-좋다!
-Let's go, Ditalion!
-Understood!
-Ayo kita mulai, Ditalion!
-Ya!
액스 노바!
Axe Nova!
해냈다!
We did it!
Berhasil!
저길 봐!
New enemies!
Musuh baru!
뭔가, 저건.
What can that be?
Apa itu?
저, 저건,
That's...
Itu...
글라디온을 넘겨라. 글라디온은 내 것이다!
Give Gladion to me. He's mine!
Serahkan Gladion. Gladion adalah milikku!
이 목소리는 데리트로스!
This voice... Deletloss!
Suara itu.... Deletloss!
뭐, 뭐야?
What the?!
A-Apa itu?!
플러그 터미널이 갑자기...
The plug terminal is suddenly...
Plug Terminalnya beroperasi sendiri...
뭐, 뭐야?
What the?!
Ada apa ini?!
잠깐, 언니, 봐봐!
Hey, sis, look at this!
Kakak, coba lihat ini!
큰, 큰일이야!
T-This is bad!
Ah, gawat!
엄마! 아빠! 봐봐! 형이!
Mom! Dad! Look at Bro!
Ayah! Ibu! Cepat! Lihat Kakak!
켄토!
Kento!
-켄토!
-뭐?!
-Kento!
-What?!
-Apa?!
글라디온은 내가 지킬 거야. 내가 부활시킬 거야.
I'm going to protect Gladion and make sure that he's revived.
Gladion akan kulindungi. Akan kubangkitkan kembali dia.
데리트로스. 절대 너 따위에게 넘겨주지 않는다!
Deletloss, I won't give him to you!
Deletloss, aku tidak akan menyerahkannya padamu!
켄토.
Kento.
쇼우.
Shou.
전세계에 발신되고 있는가.
Is it being transmitted to all over the world?
Apakah ini dipancarkan ke seluruh dunia?
켄토!
Kento!
형!
Bro!
Kakak!
켄토!
Kento!
글라디온은 안 넘겨줘! 절대!
I won't hand Gladion over to you! Never!
Gladion tidak akan kuserahkan! Tidak akan pernah!
쓰러지지 않을 거야! 계속 싸울 거야!
I won't be defeated! I won't lose!
Aku tidak akan kalah! Tidak akan kalah!
안 져! 절대 안 져!
I won't lose! I can't lose now!
Aku tidak akan kalah! Aku tidak boleh kalah!
-이번엔 내가 구할 거야! 글라디온을!
-This time, I will save Gladion!
-Kali ini, akulah yang akan menyelamatkan Gladion!
저건,
That's...
Ini...
글라디온이 켄토의 정의의 마음하고 동기화했어!
Gladion has synchronized with Kento's will of justice!
Gladion telah bersatu dengan jiwa kebenaran yang Kento miliki!
글라디온...
Gladion...
켄토. 지금이야. 네 정의의 마음으로 글라디온을 되살려!
Kento, now's the time. Revive Gladion with your will of justice!
Kento, ini saatnya. Bangkitkanlah Gladion dengan jiwa kebenaranmu!
알았어, 쇼우!
Got it, Shou!
Aku mengerti, Shou!
살아나! 글라디온!
Revive, Gladion!
Bangkitlah, Gladion!
그럴 수는 없지!
That won't happen!
Tidak akan kubiarkan!
켄토!
Kento!
다이타 스매시!
Dita Smash!
웃기지 마라!
Don't disturb me!
Kau jangan mengganggu!
데리트로스, 네가 원하는 건 절대 일어나지 않을 테다!
Deletloss, I won't let you do as you wish!
Deletloss, tidak akan kubiarkan kau bertindak sesukamu!
글라디온은 전세계의 모두를 구해 줬어. 이번엔 내 차례야. 내가 글라디온을 구할 거야.
Gladion has saved the children all over the world. Now it's my turn. I will save Gladion.
Gladion telah menyelamatkan anak-anak di seluruh dunia.
Sekarang adalah giliranku. Aku akan menyelamatkan Gladion.
-힘내, 켄토.
-힘내, 켄토!
-Do your best, Kento.
-Keep fighting, Kento!
-Berjuanglah, Kento!
형, 힘내!
Hang in there, Bro!
Kakak, bertahanlah!
기다려. 내가 반드시 구해줄 테니까.
Please hold on. I will definitely save you.
Tunggulah. Aku pasti akan menyelamatkanmu.
젠장. 글라디온을 부활시키기에 켄토가 피해를 너무 많이 입었어...
Damn. With such wound, Kento won't be able to revive Gladion.
Celaka. Kento sekarang sedang terluka. Dia tidak akan bisa membangkitkan Gladion.
쇼우!
Shou!
자, 유우키 켄토. 글라디온을 넘겨 보실까.
Now, Yuuki Kento. Give Gladion to me.
Nah, Yuuki Kento. Serahkan Gladion padahku.
절대! 난 반드시 글라디온을 되살려낼 거야! 그리고 데리트로스, 널 쓰러뜨릴 거야!
Never! I will definitely revive him! And then, we will defeat you!
Tidak akan! Aku pasti akan membangkitkan kembali Gladion! Lalu, Deletloss, kami akan mengalahkanmu!
그래? 그러면 꿈을 깨뜨려 주는 게 좋겠군!
Is that so? Alright, I will finish you off right here!
Baiklah. Kalau begitu, aku akan memusnahkanmu!
글라디온!
Gladion!
플러그 잇, 글라디온!
Plug It, Gladion!
이게 대체 뭔 일인가. 백, 천, 만, 30만.
Unbelievable. A hundred, a thousand, ten thousand, 300 thousand.
Apa yang terjadi? Seratus, seribu, sepuluh ribu, tiga ratus ribu.
글라디온이 구해준 아이들 모두의 소망이 전세계에서 이 다이버랜드로 모이고 있군!
The wishes from all children over the world who were saved by Gladion are gathered into Diverland!
Perasaan semua anak yang diselamatkan oleh Gladion akhirnya berkumpul di Diverland!
이 목소리는 뭐지.
What can this voice be?
Suara apa ini?!
느껴져.
I can feel it.
Aku bisa merasakannya.
느껴진다.
I can definitely feel it.
Aku bisa merasakannya.
이건 마음. 모두의 정의의 마음. 나에게 힘을 빌려주고 있는 거구나.
This is the will-- the will of justice from everyone. They are lending their power to me.
Ini adalah perasaan-- perasaan kebenaran dari semua anak. Kalian meminjamiku kekuatan, ya?
고마워, 모두.
Thank you, everybody.
Terima kasih, semuanya.
부활해! 글라디온!
Revive, Gladion!
Bangkitlah, Gladion!
글라디온!
Gladion!
잘 했다! 유우키 켄토!
Great job, Yuuki Kento!
Kerja bagus, Yuuki Kento!
-좋아!
-역시 형이야!
-Great!
-Brother did it!
-Bagus!
-Kakak berhasil!
-오오!
-글라디온!
-Awesome!
-Gladion!
-Dia berhasil!
켄토. 고마워. 네 덕분에 다시 살아날 수 있었다.
Kento, thank you. I could come back because of you.
Kento, terima kasih. Berkat bantuanmu, aku bisa bangkit kembali.
나뿐만이 아니야. 전세계의 아이들 모두가 응원해준 덕분이야!
It's not only me who helped. This is thanks to children all over the world!
Bukan cuma itu saja. Ini adalah berkat anak-anak di seluruh dunia!
세계의 아이들이여, 고맙다. 너희에게 받은 생명, 결코 헛되이 쓰지 않겠다.
Children from the world, thank you. I will not waste the life I've received from you.
Terima kasih, anak-anak di seluruh dunia. Jiwa yang kudapatkan dari kalian tidak akan kusia-siakan.
다이탈리온!
Ditalion!
켄토! 웹다이브해라!
Kento! Webdive!
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
글라디온. 슈퍼 액스 노바다!
Gladion, let's use Super Axe Nova!
Gladion, kita gunakan Super Axe Nova!
그 몸으로는 무리다! 나머지는 나에게 맡겨라!
It's too dangerous with that body! Just leave the rest to me!
Mustahil dengan kondisimu yang seperti itu! Selanjutnya serahkan saja padaku!
걱정 마라. 결심했다. 이 목숨을 걸고 글라디온, 너와 함께 싸우겠다고!
Do not worry. I've decided. As long as I'm still alive, I will fight together with you, Gladion!
Jangan khawatir. Selama aku masih bernyawa, aku akan terus bertarung bersamamu, Gladion!
-그렇다면야! 노바 모드로!
-좋은 선택이다!
-Then let's do this! To Nova Mode!
-Understood!
-Baik! Ayo kita lakukan! Nova Mode!
-Iya!
웹체인지! 다이탈리온, 어택 모드!
Webchange! Ditalion, Attack Mode!
글라디온! 노바 모드!
Gladion, Nova Mode!
슈퍼 액스 노바!
Super Axe Nova!
해냈다!
We did it!
Berhasil!
카론, 일어났구나.
Finally woke up, Karon?
Karon, kau sudah sadar, ya?
켄토. 끄응.
Kento.
카론, 여기서 뭐 했었어용? 악몽을 꾼 기분이야뾰꼬.
What did Karon do here-pyoko? It feels like I just had something really amazing-pyoko.
Apa yang Karon lakukan di sini-pyoko? Rasanya seperti baru mengalami sesuatu yang luar biasa.
켄토. 뭐 아는 거 있지뾰꼬! 알려줘뾰꼬!
Kento, you must have known something about this-pyoko. Tell me-pyoko!
Kento, apa kau tahu sesuatu-pyoko? Ayo beritahu aku-pyoko!
전혀 괜찮지 않으니까 알려줘뾰꼬!
Stop teasing and do tell me-pyoko!
Ayo, beritahu aku-pyoko!
좋았어! 매지컬 스테이션이 돌아왔다!
Great! Magical Station is back!
Berhasil! Magical Station muncul kembali!
그렇구나! 매지컬 스테이션도 원래대로 돌아왔으니 다행이다!
I see! Good to know that Magical Station has been recovered too! Thank goodness!
Begitu, ya! Jadi Magical Station sudah kembali seperti semula! Syukurlah!
다이탈리온도 돌아와서 마침내 13 웹나이트 모두가 있게 됐어. 이렇게 매지컬 게이트의 보안은 완벽해졌다.
Added with Ditalion, all 13 Webknights are finally here. Magical Gate is now perfectly secured.
Dengan ditambah Ditalion, akhirnya ketigabelas Webknight telah terkumpul.
Dengan ini, penjagaan Magical Gate akan sempurna.
자, 기다려라, 데리트로스! 넌 우리가 꼭 쓰러뜨리겠어!
Now you just wait, Deletloss! We will definitely take you down!
Nah, tunggu saja, Deletloss! Kami pasti akan mengalahkanmu!
Screenplay
Kubota Masashi
Storyboarding
Takata Atsushi
Staging
Ishida Hiroshi
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Asaba Naoki
Takeuchi Junko
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Kurachi Shou
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kaito
Takagi Reiko
Arisugawa Professor
Tobita Nobuo
English Boy
Makino Yoshina
Russian Girl
Kurokawa Nami
Voice Actor
Jaguaron
Kawashima Tokuyoshi
Deletloss
Fumihiko Tachiki
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Oikawa Neko
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kouno Yougo
Singer
Kageyama Hironobu
Insert Song
Dear Friend, To the Far Side of Dream
: Gladion's Theme
Lyrics
Sugita Tomokazu
Composer
Daimon Kazuya
Arranger
Singer
(Sugita Tomokazu)
Gladion
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Thank you for watching!
Production
Preview for Next Episode
돌아왔구나, 글라디온!
Welcome back, Gladion!
Selamat datang kembali, Gladion!
결국엔 모든 웹나이트가 돌아왔어.
All Webknights are back at last.
Akhirnya, semua Webknight telah kembali.
그런데 평화를 되찾은 매지컬 게이트에 또 다시 이변이 일어나서,
But, another incident happens inside the supposed-peaceful Magical Gate.
Tetapi, terjadi keanehan di Magical Gate yang semestinya telah mendapatkan kedamaian.
우리 앞에 데리트로스의 전사 류토가 나타나.
And Deletloss' warrior, Ryuto, appears in front of us.
Dan di hadapan kami, muncullah prajurit Deletloss, Ryuto.
새로운 적이 출현하고, 우리 모험이 새로 시작해.
A new enemy appears and our new adventure begins.
Musuh baru telah muncul, dan petualangan baru kami dimulai.
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !